<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-27T21:15:22+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Forum #23 - Kate Pickering with Holly Corfield Carr</title><link href="/2021/06/30/kate-pickering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #23 - Kate Pickering with Holly Corfield Carr" /><published>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/06/30/kate-pickering</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/06/30/kate-pickering.html">&lt;p&gt;Kate Pickering will share extracts from ‘There is a Miracle in your Mouth’, an experimental text formed of several threads: mythic stories of Lakewood (North America’s largest megachurch) within the broader context of American Evangelical climate crisis skepticism; an account of an oncoming hurricane based on research into hurricane Harvey; and lastly, drawing upon the writing and cell of Julian of Norwich, Pickering imagines her body as a building about to be breached by a flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/empathy-structure.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;&apos;Empathy Structure&apos; by Kate Pickering&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Empathy Structure&lt;/em&gt; (2017) Performance, Ben Pimlott Building, Goldsmiths. Image courtesy: Original&amp;amp;TheCopy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate Pickering is a London based artist, writer and PhD researcher (CHASE scholarship) in the departments of Art and Visual Cultures at Goldsmiths. Pickering writes experimental prose poetry which she develops into performative readings exploring notions of body, belief and site. The focus of her research is the Evangelical megachurch, specifically how the narrative of Evangelicalism is mediated through performance, spectacle, site and scale to dis/orient the believer in the world, and how a performative poetics might reorient the believer toward a fluid imaginary. Her writing has featured in various publications, including soanyway magazine, Misery Connoisseur, EROS journal, Yellow Pages (Copy Press) and KONESH, and has been performed at Tenderpixel, ASC Gallery, X Marks Le Bokship, Library Gallery (Winnipeg, Canada), the Barbican and the ICA. She has presented her research at conferences at Goldsmiths, Birkbeck, the Courtauld Institute of Art and the University of Essex and has forthcoming book chapters in ‘Imagining the Apocalypse’ which will be published by Courtauld Books Online, and ‘Fieldwork for Future Ecologies’ (working title) to be published by Onomatopee. Pickering initiated the Writing for Practice Forum for artists who write, and participates in Wet Rest, run by Lucy A. Sames and the Liquidity Cohort, a research group run by Bridget Crone. 
kate-pickering.com
instagram.com/writing_a_body_of_belief&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holly Corfield Carr is a writer and poet. Recent publications include poetry in POETRY (Chicago), short fiction on BBC Radio 4, audio and text installations for the Hayward Gallery (London) and two books of poetry and image, Indifferent Cresses and Subsong, both commissioned by the National Trust in connection with two residencies, the first in a woodland, the second on a headland. She has held residencies and fellowships at Spike Island (Bristol), the Henry Moore Institute (Leeds) and the Wordsworth Trust (Grasmere) and she is currently a Research Fellow in English at Murray Edwards College, University of Cambridge where she works on site-specific writing practices with a particular interest in caves and holes in the landscape. She received an Eric Gregory Award in 2012 and the Frieze Writer’s Prize in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Kate Pickering will share extracts from ‘There is a Miracle in your Mouth’, an experimental text formed of several threads: mythic stories of Lakewood (North America’s largest megachurch) within the broader context of American Evangelical climate crisis skepticism; an account of an oncoming hurricane based on research into hurricane Harvey; and lastly, drawing upon the writing and cell of Julian of Norwich, Pickering imagines her body as a building about to be breached by a flood.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #5 - Guilia Damiani with Kristen Kreider</title><link href="/2018/12/05/Guilia-Damiani.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #5 - Guilia Damiani with Kristen Kreider" /><published>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/12/05/Guilia-Damiani</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/12/05/Guilia-Damiani.html">&lt;p&gt;Writer and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Guilia Damiani presents new writing entitled As Enchentes Entre Os Incêndios (trans. *the water rivulets among the fire) alongside an excerpt from The Passion According to GH by writer Clarice Lispector, and artist, writer and Professor of Fine Art Kristen Kreider joins us in discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guilia Damiani is a writer and curator based in London, completing a PhD in Art at Goldsmiths University (AHRC scholarship). She specialises in performance and collaborates with artists to create performances from archival and feminist practices. She is currently a Research and Writing Fellow at the institution If I Can’t Dance, I Don’t Want to be Part of Your Revolution, Amsterdam. – giuliadamiani.eu&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kristen Kreider is a writer and artist. Her research stems from an interest in the poetics of thought, its materialization as form, and a concern with how artworks relate to the world. She has published poetry, essays, journal articles and a single-authored monograph entitled Poetics &amp;amp; Place: The Architecture of Sign, Subject and Site (IB Tauris, 2014). The latter explores how specific artworks generate meaning through a ‘material poetics’ in relation to place, develops a critical methodology for engaging with them, and investigates their ethical potential and political imperative. The book concludes with a discussion of the ethics of relation, opening a debate concerning the role of empathy within contemporary, politically-engaged practices in art and poetry. – gold.ac.uk/art/staff/kreider-kristen&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Writer and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Guilia Damiani presents new writing entitled As Enchentes Entre Os Incêndios (trans. *the water rivulets among the fire) alongside an excerpt from The Passion According to GH by writer Clarice Lispector, and artist, writer and Professor of Fine Art Kristen Kreider joins us in discussion.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #4 - Sophie Sleigh-Johnson</title><link href="/2018/08/17/Sophie-Sleigh-Johnson.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #4 - Sophie Sleigh-Johnson" /><published>2018-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-08-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/08/17/Sophie-Sleigh-Johnson</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/08/17/Sophie-Sleigh-Johnson.html">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Sophie Sleigh-Johnson presents new prose alongside an excerpt from The Baphomet by Pierre Klossowski and Abstract by William S. Boroughs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sophie Sleigh-Johnson is an artist based in Southend-on-Sea, Essex. With a background in music, the practice involves sonic and spoken performances. She is working on a PhD at Goldsmiths College called Radio Bifrons: Broadcasting From The Crypt. Recent projects include Cealdwiellla with New Noveta, Machine of Instant Utility at Cabinet Gallery (group show) and occasional broadcasts of Chthonic Live on Resonance 104.4 FM. In 2015 she published Chthonic Index in collaboration with Simon Martin and Timothy Morton. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sophiesleigh-johnson.co.uk&quot;&gt;sophiesleigh-johnson.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Sophie Sleigh-Johnson presents new prose alongside an excerpt from The Baphomet by Pierre Klossowski and Abstract by William S. Boroughs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #3 - Ciarán Ó Dochartaigh</title><link href="/2018/07/27/ciaran-o-dochartaigh.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #3 - Ciarán Ó Dochartaigh" /><published>2018-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/07/27/ciaran-o-dochartaigh</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/27/ciaran-o-dochartaigh.html">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Ciarán Ó Dochartaigh presents new writing in the form of a prose work entitled Fish, together with a script entitled Choreographing death and The Indian Meal - A Proposal for a theatre piece, and a poem entitled Clay Sausages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ciarán Ó Dochartaigh is an interdisciplinary visual artist with an interest in materiality, in particular the intersections between material and immaterial processes. Ciarán is a PhD researcher in the art department at Goldsmiths. His research explores complexities inherent within post conflict trauma and is interested in intergenerational trauma and how it manifests. As part of his research Ó Dochartaigh has an ongoing research relationship with a family of donkeys and African land snails, exploring interspecies relationships and kinship. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ciaranodochartaigh.org&quot;&gt;ciaranodochartaigh.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Ciarán Ó Dochartaigh presents new writing in the form of a prose work entitled Fish, together with a script entitled Choreographing death and The Indian Meal - A Proposal for a theatre piece, and a poem entitled Clay Sausages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #2 - Kate Pickering</title><link href="/2018/07/03/kate-pickering.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #2 - Kate Pickering" /><published>2018-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/07/03/kate-pickering</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/07/03/kate-pickering.html">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Kate Pickering presents the script of a recent performance piece entitled Cell alongside Cell: an introduction to a Response by poet, writer and researcher Holly Corfield Carr (University of Cambridge).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kate Pickering is a London based artist, writer and PhD researcher in the departments of Art and Visual Cultures at Goldsmiths. She investigates belief as embodied narrative through research into Evangelical megachurches, focusing on how a body is dis/oriented within the megachurch through material, visual and fabulatory conditions. This research is extended into performative site based readings. – kate-pickering.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Kate Pickering presents the script of a recent performance piece entitled Cell alongside Cell: an introduction to a Response by poet, writer and researcher Holly Corfield Carr (University of Cambridge).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #1 - Rowena Harris</title><link href="/2018/06/20/rowena-harris.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #1 - Rowena Harris" /><published>2018-06-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2018/06/20/rowena-harris</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/06/20/rowena-harris.html">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Rowena Harris presents a short creative text entitled How to be Slow together with Thinking Impossibly (a guide) - a publication which formed part of an installation at her recent exhibition, and presents for discussion the title chapter from author Dodie Bellamy’s book When the Sick Rule the World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to texts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowena Harris is an artist and PhD candidate at Goldsmiths. Her research encompasses theories on the datalogical in relation to neuroatypicality, pursued through creative writing, material practice, and film work. Within she explores a relation between systemic use of cognitive enhancements by Silicon Valley and the contemporary system by which the datalogical functions, seeking to give voice to neuroatypical people that maybe absent from this space, and to consider another place of thinking differently. – rowenaharris.com&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>katarina</name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher (Goldsmiths) Rowena Harris presents a short creative text entitled How to be Slow together with Thinking Impossibly (a guide) - a publication which formed part of an installation at her recent exhibition, and presents for discussion the title chapter from author Dodie Bellamy’s book When the Sick Rule the World.</summary></entry></feed>