<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-30T17:12:45+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Writing for Practice Forum</title><entry><title type="html">Forum #24 - Dani Smith with Zoë Mendelson</title><link href="/2021/07/26/danielle-smith/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #24 - Dani Smith with Zoë Mendelson" /><published>2021-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-07-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/07/26/danielle-smith</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/07/26/danielle-smith/">&lt;p&gt;Dani Smith will present excerpts from a collection of d​iary entries detailing her time returning home to Los Banos, a small farming town in central California, for Christmas 2020. Writings that emerged from this time, observe the bending, breaking, and adjusting of her psyche as it reacts to the shape shifting home environment and growing pains of evolving family dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dani Smith&lt;/strong&gt; is a painter and writer in her first year of PhD research at Goldsmiths, University of London. Her research project: &lt;em&gt;So the Cursed May Conjure&lt;/em&gt;, is a spiritual exploration of selfhood that engages the mechanics of black feminism and autotheory to query a range of metaphysical trauma as withstanding effects of normalised violences against black female bodies. Converging intimate storytelling and multidisciplinary painting methods, Dani’s practice illustrates examples of modern black female misrepresentations, its various forms of consequences, and executions of resistance against prevailing ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoë Mendelson&lt;/strong&gt; has an expanded field practice that owes its spatialisation, historical narratives and compositional framework to painting. She has exhibited and performed widely in the UK and abroad, including Fondation Cartier, Paris; CRAC Alsace, Chapter, Cardiff and Science Museum, London. Zoë’s research engages disorder as a culturally produced phenomenon, in parallel to its clinical counterpart. She has a PhD from Central St Martins and is Head of Painting and Printmaking at Glasgow School of Art. Zoë co-curates the network &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paintingresearch.net/&quot;&gt;paintingresearch&lt;/a&gt; with Geraint Evans and is co-founder and editor of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theedit.site/&quot;&gt;The Edit&lt;/a&gt;, an online inclusive, de-canonised bibliography for students in Fine Art and related fields, now used in Arts education internationally.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dani Smith will present excerpts from a collection of d​iary entries detailing her time returning home to Los Banos, a small farming town in central California, for Christmas 2020. Writings that emerged from this time, observe the bending, breaking, and adjusting of her psyche as it reacts to the shape shifting home environment and growing pains of evolving family dynamics.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #23 - Kate Pickering with Holly Corfield Carr</title><link href="/2021/06/30/kate-pickering/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #23 - Kate Pickering with Holly Corfield Carr" /><published>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/06/30/kate-pickering</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/06/30/kate-pickering/">&lt;p&gt;Kate Pickering will share extracts from &lt;em&gt;There is a Miracle in your Mouth&lt;/em&gt;, an experimental text formed of several threads: mythic stories of Lakewood (North America’s largest megachurch) within the broader context of American Evangelical climate crisis skepticism; an account of an oncoming hurricane based on research into hurricane Harvey; and lastly, drawing upon the writing and cell of Julian of Norwich, Pickering imagines her body as a building about to be breached by a flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kate Pickering&lt;/strong&gt; is a London based artist, writer and PhD researcher (CHASE scholarship) in the departments of Art and Visual Cultures at Goldsmiths. Pickering writes experimental prose poetry which she develops into performative readings exploring notions of body, belief and site. The focus of her research is the Evangelical megachurch, specifically how the narrative of Evangelicalism is mediated through performance, spectacle, site and scale to dis/orient the believer in the world, and how a performative poetics might reorient the believer toward a fluid imaginary. Her writing has featured in various publications, including soanyway magazine, Misery Connoisseur, EROS journal, Yellow Pages (Copy Press) and KONESH, and has been performed at Tenderpixel, ASC Gallery, X Marks Le Bokship, Library Gallery (Winnipeg, Canada), the Barbican and the ICA. She has presented her research at conferences at Goldsmiths, Birkbeck, the Courtauld Institute of Art and the University of Essex and has forthcoming book chapters in &lt;em&gt;Imagining the Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; which will be published by Courtauld Books Online, and &lt;em&gt;Fieldwork for Future Ecologies&lt;/em&gt; (working title) to be published by Onomatopee. Pickering initiated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://writingforpracticeforum.github.io/&quot;&gt;Writing for Practice Forum&lt;/a&gt; for artists who write, and participates in Wet Rest, run by Lucy A. Sames and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://m-a-r-s.online/gatherings/liquid-bodies-worlds-series-2&quot;&gt;Liquidity Cohort&lt;/a&gt;, a research group run by Bridget Crone. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kate-pickering.com&quot;&gt;kate-pickering.com&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instagram.com/writing_a_body_of_belief&quot;&gt;@writing_a_body_of_belief&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holly Corfield Carr&lt;/strong&gt; is a writer and poet. Recent publications include poetry in POETRY (Chicago), short fiction on BBC Radio 4, audio and text installations for the Hayward Gallery (London) and two books of poetry and image, &lt;em&gt;Indifferent Cresses&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Subsong&lt;/em&gt;, both commissioned by the National Trust in connection with two residencies, the first in a woodland, the second on a headland. She has held residencies and fellowships at Spike Island (Bristol), the Henry Moore Institute (Leeds) and the Wordsworth Trust (Grasmere) and she is currently a Research Fellow in English at Murray Edwards College, University of Cambridge where she works on site-specific writing practices with a particular interest in caves and holes in the landscape. She received an Eric Gregory Award in 2012 and the Frieze Writer’s Prize in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Kate Pickering will share extracts from There is a Miracle in your Mouth, an experimental text formed of several threads: mythic stories of Lakewood (North America’s largest megachurch) within the broader context of American Evangelical climate crisis skepticism; an account of an oncoming hurricane based on research into hurricane Harvey; and lastly, drawing upon the writing and cell of Julian of Norwich, Pickering imagines her body as a building about to be breached by a flood.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #22 - Emma Bolland with Ceri Morgan</title><link href="/2021/06/17/emma-bolland/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #22 - Emma Bolland with Ceri Morgan" /><published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/06/17/emma-bolland</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/06/17/emma-bolland/">&lt;p&gt;Emma Bolland will present &lt;em&gt;Instructions from Light&lt;/em&gt;, a hybrid novella / long poem that turns on a translation and ‘writing through’ of Louis Delluc’s impressionist screenplay &lt;em&gt;Le Silence&lt;/em&gt; (1920). This work will be considered alongside extracts from texts by Anne Carson and Maria Fusco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emma Bolland&lt;/strong&gt; is an artist and writer whose practice includes an investigation of the problematics and ambiguities of an expanded understanding of translation—between languages and language codes, and between modes of writing, reading and speaking. Emma is a co-editor at Gordian Projects, an Associate Lecturer at Sheffield Hallam University, co-runner of Radio oHPo, and were the 2019 #&lt;em&gt;interrupteur&lt;/em&gt; artist-writer in residence for the School of Arts and Humanities at the University of Sheffield. Recent publications include ‘Subjects of the Gaze: script development as performance’, co-authored with Louise Sawtell, in &lt;em&gt;Script Development: Critical Approaches, Creative Practices, International Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;, eds. Craig Batty and Stayci Taylor (Palgrave MacMillan 2021), ‘The Fiction of the Essay: Of Abstraction, Texts, Communication, and Loss’, co-authored with Elizabeth Chakrabarty, in &lt;em&gt;Imagined Spaces&lt;/em&gt;, eds. Gail Low and Kirsty Young (Voyages Out, 2020), and &lt;em&gt;Over, In, and Under&lt;/em&gt; (Dostoevsky Wannabe, 2019). A bilingual English/German audio work will be included in the forthcoming exhibition &lt;a href=&quot;https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/CZ9ACvZ9NFqmZ7WcQmdGZ?domain=mewo-kunsthalle.de&quot;&gt;imPERFEKT —eine Ausstellung zur Barrierefreiheit&lt;/a&gt;, MEWO Kunsthall, Memmingen, Germany. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emmabolland.com&quot;&gt;emmabolland.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ceri Morgan&lt;/strong&gt; is Senior Lecturer in English and Creative Writing at Keele University and works on literary geographies, place-writing, geopoetics (site-responsive creative practices), walking studies, and geohumanities. A specialist of Québec fiction, Ceri has worked on projects on Montreal, ’urbs (suburban, exurban, and rural spaces), and regions. Key themes besides the spatial include language and translation, mobilities and belonging, memory, temporality, and identity. Since 2014, she has worked increasingly on geopoetics as a participatory practice, and has led workshops on a variety of themes, including mining, food, persistent pain, and deindustrialisation. In April 2020, Ceri set up an online reading and writing group, &lt;em&gt;Microclimates&lt;/em&gt;, in response to social and spatial restrictions prompted by the pandemic. She has published some fiction, creative nonfiction, and prose-poetry, notably in &lt;em&gt;Littoral&lt;/em&gt; (2017), &lt;em&gt;GeoHumanities&lt;/em&gt; (2019), and &lt;em&gt;NAWE Writing in Education&lt;/em&gt; (2020). Her prose-poem, ‘Avenue Bernard’ was broadcast on RTE Radio 1 extra and RTE Radio 1 in Spring and Summer 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Emma Bolland will present Instructions from Light, a hybrid novella / long poem that turns on a translation and ‘writing through’ of Louis Delluc’s impressionist screenplay Le Silence (1920). This work will be considered alongside extracts from texts by Anne Carson and Maria Fusco.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #21 - Rachel Smith with Karenjit Sandhu</title><link href="/2021/05/26/rachel-smith/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #21 - Rachel Smith with Karenjit Sandhu" /><published>2021-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/05/26/rachel-smith</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/05/26/rachel-smith/">&lt;p&gt;Rachel Smith will present some excerpts from a new work which takes an insolent but smitten route through an existing text. The work forms part of the wider development of her read(writ)ing method using drawing, photography, and writing and will be accompanied by reading fragments from Karen Barad, Roland Barthes, and Hélène Cixous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rachel Smith&lt;/strong&gt; is an artist and educator with a practice across Drawing, Photography, and Writing. She completed her PhD at Sheffield Hallam University in May 2020: &lt;em&gt;Drawing out Language: From Or to And, Disrupting Dualism through Conceptual Poetics&lt;/em&gt;. She is interested in the production of artist books, using the page space to explore hybrid image and text experiments. Her work meanders through existing texts, fragmenting narratives, appropriating text, and materialising association, error, and distraction to visualise how sense might be sought, rejected, and re-fused. As part of her Ph.D. research, she developed a method which explores the act of reading as writing as making — &lt;em&gt;read(writ)ing&lt;/em&gt; — the term underpins her practice which cuts together-apart processes related to these actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She has exhibited widely in the UK, recently having her work, &lt;em&gt;Catching sight of the Salt cellar&lt;/em&gt;, included in the group show: The Salon for a Speculative Future at Chisenhale Studios, London and the resulting compendium of work, published by MA Bibliotheque. She took part in the first &lt;em&gt;Interrupteur&lt;/em&gt; Artist residency in the faculty of Humanities at the University of Sheffield in 2018. This two-month residency involved working with Artists and forging dialogue with Academics from the Humanities dept. to explore and create collaborations between practice and research ideas. Her latest book &lt;em&gt;Read(writ)ing words: a meandering material dialogue&lt;/em&gt; is available from Penteract Press, and she has been interviewed for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://penteractpress.com/p-p-p/2020/6/6/episode-07-rachel-smith&quot;&gt;Penteract Poetry Podcast&lt;/a&gt;. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rachelartsmith.com&quot;&gt;rachelartsmith.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karenjit Sandhu&lt;/strong&gt; is a poet and artist. Her poems are forthcoming in &lt;em&gt;Judith: Women Making Visual Poetry&lt;/em&gt; (Timglaset Editions, 2021), and her debut poetry collection titled &lt;em&gt;Young Girls&lt;/em&gt; will be released later this year by the 87 Press. Her work has been published in the following magazines and anthologies: &lt;em&gt;Magma&lt;/em&gt; (2020), &lt;em&gt;Writing Utopia&lt;/em&gt; (Hesterglock Press, 2020), &lt;em&gt;Nemeses&lt;/em&gt; (HVTN Press, 2019) and &lt;em&gt;Para-text&lt;/em&gt; (2019). Her poetry is also available online at &lt;em&gt;Digital Poetics&lt;/em&gt; (87 Press, 2020), &lt;em&gt;Junction Box&lt;/em&gt; (2020) and &lt;em&gt;DATABLEED&lt;/em&gt; (2019). Her performance work has been commissioned by the Sir Denis Mahon Foundation, and she has collaborated with the Institute of Contemporary Arts, Flat Time House and Camden People’s Theatre (London), Arnolfini (Bristol) and Galerie Eric Dupont (Paris). She has also written for &lt;em&gt;The Blue Notebook: Journal for Artists’ Books&lt;/em&gt; (2010), and her artworks have been exhibited at The Showroom (London) and Galerie éof (Paris).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Rachel Smith will present some excerpts from a new work which takes an insolent but smitten route through an existing text. The work forms part of the wider development of her read(writ)ing method using drawing, photography, and writing and will be accompanied by reading fragments from Karen Barad, Roland Barthes, and Hélène Cixous.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #20 - Daniela Cascella with Jennifer Hodgson</title><link href="/2021/04/19/daniela-cascella/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #20 - Daniela Cascella with Jennifer Hodgson" /><published>2021-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2021/04/19/daniela-cascella</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/04/19/daniela-cascella/">&lt;p&gt;Daniela (Sheffield Hallam University) will present an excerpt from her ongoing project on Chimeric Writing, along with extracts from &lt;a href=&quot;https://squint.press/01a_viviandarroch-lozowski_voiceofhearing/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Voice of Hearing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Vivian Darroch-Lozowski, Squint Press, 2020 (1984) and &lt;em&gt;Mundus imaginalis or The Imaginary and the Imaginal&lt;/em&gt; by Henry Corbin (1972).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniela Cascella&lt;/strong&gt; is an Italian writer whose texts articulate tensions and points of contact between the literary and the sonic, and propose a range of approaches to creative-critical writing through experiments with form and voice. She is the author, in English, of &lt;em&gt;Singed&lt;/em&gt; (Equus Press, 2017), F.M.R.L. (Zer0 Books, 2015), &lt;em&gt;En Abîme&lt;/em&gt; (Zer0 Books, 2012); and in Italian, of &lt;em&gt;The Cure: The Edge of the World&lt;/em&gt; (Arcana, 2008), and &lt;em&gt;Scultori di suono&lt;/em&gt; (Tuttle, 2005). Daniela lectures and publishes internationally, and often collaborates with musicians and artists in readings and editorial/curatorial projects. She is an Associate Lecturer in the MA Sound Arts at LCC / University of the Arts London, and is completing her Ph.D. at Sheffield Hallam University where she has been developing a project around Chimeric Writing that will result in two books, the former of which is forthcoming on &lt;a href=&quot;https://punctumbooks.com/imprints/risking-education/&quot;&gt;Risking Education / Punctum Books&lt;/a&gt;. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danielacascella.com&quot;&gt;danielacascella.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jennifer Hodgson&lt;/strong&gt; is a writer and editor based in London. She is Editor-at-large at The White Review and the programmer and host of Humbermouth Literature Festival, Hull. In 2018 she published &lt;em&gt;The Unmapped Country&lt;/em&gt;, the collected short stories of the sixties writer, Ann Quin. She is currently working on a hybrid non-fiction project based on Quin’s life that explores narrative and non-narrative forms of living, expanded experiences of consciousness and our attachments (and resistances) to writers and their work. She was previously Research Fellow at Hearing the Voice (Durham University) a Wellcome Trust-funded project investigating the phenomenon of auditory vocal hallucinations, where she led a study into voice-hearing and creativity. Prior to that, she was UK Editor at Dalkey Archive Press.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Daniela (Sheffield Hallam University) will present an excerpt from her ongoing project on Chimeric Writing, along with extracts from Voice of Hearing by Vivian Darroch-Lozowski, Squint Press, 2020 (1984) and Mundus imaginalis or The Imaginary and the Imaginal by Henry Corbin (1972).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #19 - Morag Colquhoun with Professor Julian Henriques</title><link href="/2021/03/22/morag-colquhoun/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #19 - Morag Colquhoun with Professor Julian Henriques" /><published>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2021/03/22/morag-colquhoun</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/03/22/morag-colquhoun/">&lt;p&gt;Morag Colquhoun will present some excerpts of new writing exploring sub/versions of rhythm together with extracts from Ralph Ellison’s &lt;em&gt;Invisible Man&lt;/em&gt; (1947) and a passage from &lt;em&gt;Architecture and the Text: The (S)crypts of Joyce and Piranesi&lt;/em&gt; by Jennifer Bloomer (1993).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morag Colquhoun&lt;/strong&gt; is an artist based in mid Wales. As a PhD researcher in the Art Department at Goldsmiths, her project, &lt;em&gt;Trofannolismo&lt;/em&gt;, reimagines a planetary Tropicália from a perspective of rural Wales. Working with Welsh communities while focusing on communities in South America that are known to her, recent manifestations of her project include: &lt;em&gt;Eden&lt;/em&gt; (2019), commissioned for Ty Pawb, Wrexham, and the National Eisteddfod of Wales, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professor Julian Henriques&lt;/strong&gt; is convenor of the MA Cultural Studies programme, director of the Topology Research Unit and a co-founder of the Sound System Outernational practice research group in the Department of Media, Communications and Cultural Studies, Goldsmiths, University of London. Prior to this, Julian ran the film and television department at CARIMAC at the University of the West Indies, Kingston, Jamaica. His credits as a writer and director include the reggae musical feature film &lt;em&gt;Babymother&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;We the Ragamuffin&lt;/em&gt; short. Julian researches street cultures, music and technologies and is interested in the uses of sound as a critical and creative tool. His sound sculptures include &lt;em&gt;Knots &amp;amp; Donuts&lt;/em&gt; (2011) at Tate Modern and his books include &lt;em&gt;Changing the Subject&lt;/em&gt; (1998), &lt;em&gt;Sonic Bodies&lt;/em&gt; (2011) and &lt;em&gt;Sonic Media&lt;/em&gt; (forthcoming). He is currently the PI on an ERC Consolidator research grant, Sonic Street Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Morag Colquhoun will present some excerpts of new writing exploring sub/versions of rhythm together with extracts from Ralph Ellison’s Invisible Man (1947) and a passage from Architecture and the Text: The (S)crypts of Joyce and Piranesi by Jennifer Bloomer (1993).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #18 - Katharina Ludwig with Mira Mattar</title><link href="/2020/12/14/katharina-ludwig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #18 - Katharina Ludwig with Mira Mattar" /><published>2020-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/12/14/katharina-ludwig</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/12/14/katharina-ludwig/">&lt;p&gt;Artist, writer and PhD researcher Katharina Ludwig will present a text that has taken multiple forms: a performance lecture, artwork, conference “paper”, image description, and extended poem. Written through a poem by anarchist poet Katerina Gogou, the text addresses character study, names, speaking and writing through each other, channelling voices, radical poetry as incantation, and wounded and holey text. It will be read alongside a poem by Sean Bonney. Fiction writer and poet Mira Mattar joins us as respondent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katharina Ludwig&lt;/strong&gt; writes and makes art. Her artworks comprise text, installation and objects. Her research in the framework of the Art Research programme at Goldsmiths, University of London, is concerned with narrative holes in women’s writing and the temporalities of the “wounded text”. Katharina tries to activate textual holes as a subversive feminist practice of resistance with insurrectional potential that treats textual wounds as a political and writerly strategy in opposition to authoritarian systems. Her work has been shown, performed or read internationally and is published by a.o. 3am Magazine, Zeno Press, Chris Airlines, MaBibliothèque.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mira Mattar&lt;/strong&gt; writes fiction and poetry. She is an independent researcher, editor, and tutor. A Palestinian/Jordanian born in the suburbs of London, she continues to live and work there. Her first book, &lt;em&gt;Yes, I Am A Destroyer&lt;/em&gt; was recently published by Ma Bibliothèque. Her first chapbook, &lt;em&gt;Affiliation&lt;/em&gt;, is forthcoming from Sad Press; and her first collection of poems will be published by The 87 Press.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Artist, writer and PhD researcher Katharina Ludwig will present a text that has taken multiple forms: a performance lecture, artwork, conference “paper”, image description, and extended poem. Written through a poem by anarchist poet Katerina Gogou, the text addresses character study, names, speaking and writing through each other, channelling voices, radical poetry as incantation, and wounded and holey text. It will be read alongside a poem by Sean Bonney. Fiction writer and poet Mira Mattar joins us as respondent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #17 - Julia Calver with Dr Karen Di Franco</title><link href="/2020/11/12/julia-calver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #17 - Julia Calver with Dr Karen Di Franco" /><published>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-11-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2020/11/12/julia-calver</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/11/12/julia-calver/">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher Julia Calver (Sheffield Hallam University) will present some work in progress which investigates the vocalised distribution of text, practices of transcription, and how accidence (inflectional morphology) can be used to disrupt the material structuring of prose. Curator and writer Dr Karen Di Franco joins us as respondent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia Calver&lt;/strong&gt; is an artist and writer who investigates how syntax, as a material structuring of language, can be re-shaped through reading, embodiment, and processes of listening. She is a practice-based researcher at Sheffield Hallam University and has performed at Whitechapel gallery, David Roberts Art Foundation, Spike Island and X Marks the Bokship. Her work has featured in The Stinging Fly, The Kink in the Arc, The Arrow Maker, Full Stop and Makhzin and has been commissioned by FormContent and distributed by Art on the Underground. Recent publications include &lt;em&gt;Nightsweats&lt;/em&gt; produced by Guillaume Vandame and &lt;em&gt;On Care&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Roland Barthes’s Party&lt;/em&gt;, both published by MA BIBLIOTHÈQUE. — &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juliacalver.co.uk&quot;&gt;juliacalver.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Karen Di Franco&lt;/strong&gt; is a curator and writer working within the contexts of archives and publishing, with a focus on practices that emerge between text and performance, the page and the body. Her PhD, (2015-20) titled &lt;em&gt;Embodied Iteration: Materialising the Language of Writing and Performance in Women Artists’ Publishing, 1968–1979&lt;/em&gt;, was supported by the AHRC/University of Reading and based at the library and archive at Tate. Frequently concerned with an inter-generational dialogue with these forms, Di Franco has curated exhibitions that incorporate materials described as ephemeral, yet resistant to categorisation. Recent projects include: &lt;em&gt;WE WILL PLUCK OUR MAGIC TWANGERS&lt;/em&gt; (artists’ film screening, Whitechapel Gallery, 2019, co-curated with Irene Revell); &lt;em&gt;Evidentiary Bodies: Celebrating Barbara Hammer &amp;amp; Carolee Schneemann&lt;/em&gt; (screening at LUX, 2019); &lt;em&gt;ORGASMIC STREAMING ORGANIC GARDENING ELECTROCULTURE&lt;/em&gt; (Group exhibition, Chelsea Space, 2018, co-curated with Irene Revell). Di Franco writes on publishing and feminist practices regularly for magazines such as Art Monthly and Art Review and has contributed long form essays on Constance DeJong and Kathy Acker for &lt;em&gt;Bricks From the Kiln&lt;/em&gt; (forthcoming 2020) and &lt;em&gt;Tinted Window&lt;/em&gt; (issue 2, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher Julia Calver (Sheffield Hallam University) will present some work in progress which investigates the vocalised distribution of text, practices of transcription, and how accidence (inflectional morphology) can be used to disrupt the material structuring of prose. Curator and writer Dr Karen Di Franco joins us as respondent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #16 - Debbie Kent with Helen Frosi</title><link href="/2020/07/13/debbie-kent/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #16 - Debbie Kent with Helen Frosi" /><published>2020-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2020/07/13/debbie-kent</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/07/13/debbie-kent/">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher Debbie Kent (Goldsmiths) will present some text that wrestles with the difficulty of describing and communicating the experience of soundscapes. Interdisciplinary artist, curator and producer Helen Frosi joins us as respondent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Debbie Kent&lt;/strong&gt;: I work with sound, cities and walking. I’m currently making a set of audio walks tracking transformations in the urban soundscape for a practise-based PhD in the Visual Cultures department. I work with the spontaneous and transient; with disassembling language and retrieving detritus from the cracks in the everyday. In the past I’ve exchanged words from Bruce Springsteen lyrics with members of the public, reassembled news stories using only the conjunctions and articles, and read from the writings of George Perec after putting the pages through a shredder. Recently I have been working in collaboration with Russian artist Alisa Oleva as the Demolition Project, making work that explores ways of reimagining the city and our relationship with it, in London, Berlin, Belgrade, Vilnius, Ekaterinburg and Moscow. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dejakay.co.uk&quot;&gt;dejakay.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Helen Frosi&lt;/strong&gt; is an interdisciplinary artist, curator and producer whose practice pivots around ecological thought, poetics, aspects of gifting and alternative forms of economy, with a focus on the creative, social, and political dimension of sound and listening. Her practice manifests as process, and necessitates collaborative, cross-disciplinary work, communal projects and collective activities. Helen is Co-Curator of Longplayer Day, a festival focusing on time, duration and long-term and ecological thinking, and her latest project, EnCOUnTErs, sits at the nexus between art and ecology, with a focus on the sonic imagination. Helen is Director of SoundFjord a nomadic curatorial platform focussed on sound-related research and practice, Founder of Visible Near Midnight Recordings for works that fall between the genre gaps, and a honorary research fellow at Goldsmiths, University of London. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.soundfjord.org&quot;&gt;soundfjord.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher Debbie Kent (Goldsmiths) will present some text that wrestles with the difficulty of describing and communicating the experience of soundscapes. Interdisciplinary artist, curator and producer Helen Frosi joins us as respondent. Debbie Kent: I work with sound, cities and walking. I’m currently making a set of audio walks tracking transformations in the urban soundscape for a practise-based PhD in the Visual Cultures department. I work with the spontaneous and transient; with disassembling language and retrieving detritus from the cracks in the everyday. In the past I’ve exchanged words from Bruce Springsteen lyrics with members of the public, reassembled news stories using only the conjunctions and articles, and read from the writings of George Perec after putting the pages through a shredder. Recently I have been working in collaboration with Russian artist Alisa Oleva as the Demolition Project, making work that explores ways of reimagining the city and our relationship with it, in London, Berlin, Belgrade, Vilnius, Ekaterinburg and Moscow. – dejakay.co.uk</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forum #15 - Katarina Ranković with Andy Holden</title><link href="/2020/06/15/katarina-rankovic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forum #15 - Katarina Ranković with Andy Holden" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/2020/06/15/katarina-rankovic</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2020/06/15/katarina-rankovic/">&lt;p&gt;Artist and PhD researcher Katarina Ranković (Goldsmiths) will present an extract from her novel &lt;em&gt;Anomaline&lt;/em&gt;, a philosophical romance about a solitary protagonist navigating the vacated vestiges of a cliche literary world, and artist and musician Andy Holden joins us as respondent in discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Katarina Ranković&lt;/strong&gt; is a text-based artist exploring the extent to which personhood is encoded in character, and whether fictional characters can be reverse-engineered into something approximating persons; into literary prototypes of general artificial intelligence. Recent projects involve &lt;em&gt;Anomaline&lt;/em&gt;, a novel about a lethargic antiperson; and using personality tests on her performed fictional characters, in a bid to problematise the distinction between ‘genuine’ being and ‘disingenuous’ performing. As a Serb-born-in-Yorkshire-raised-in-Norway, both the theory and practice of Katarina’s work originates from the daily necessity of inhabiting and switching between many selves. – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.katarinarankovic.art&quot;&gt;katarinarankovic.art&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andy Holden&lt;/strong&gt; (b. 1982) artist, musician and cartoon was born and now lives and works in Bedford, UK. Holden has worked collaboratively with his father Peter Holden, an orthologist, to produce lectures on birds and the recent Artangel project Natural Selection. He regularly performs and releases records with his band &lt;em&gt;The Grubby Mitts&lt;/em&gt; and runs the project space &lt;em&gt;Ex-Baldessarre&lt;/em&gt; in Bedford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His most recent solo exhibitions include &lt;em&gt;Natural Selection&lt;/em&gt; at Bristol Museum and Art Gallery, LEEDS Art Gallery and Towner Gallery, &lt;em&gt;Laws of Motion in a Cartoon Landscape&lt;/em&gt;, Glasgow International (2016) and FGAP at Venice Biennale (2017); &lt;em&gt;Towards a Unified Theory of MI!MS&lt;/em&gt;, Zabludowicz Collection, London (2013), Spike Island (2014); &lt;em&gt;Chewy Cosmos Thingly Time&lt;/em&gt;, Kettle’s Yard, Cambridge (2011); and &lt;em&gt;Art Now: Andy Holden&lt;/em&gt;, Tate Britain (2010). – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.andyholdenartist.com&quot;&gt;andyholdenartist.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Artist and PhD researcher Katarina Ranković (Goldsmiths) will present an extract from her novel Anomaline, a philosophical romance about a solitary protagonist navigating the vacated vestiges of a cliche literary world, and artist and musician Andy Holden joins us as respondent in discussion.</summary></entry></feed>